this video is sponsored by YouTube and
Eurosport I am getting older I'm 34 now
and that term mid 30s well that's what
I'm in it doesn't feel good to hear that
lately I've been thinking a lot about
taking care of myself better to prolong
my ability to do things that I like
which is making videos and climbing and
making videos about climbing seriously
I've made so much climbing content I had
to make a second Channel all about
climbing H cuz there was too much going
on here if you know this channel you'll
know that I go through periods of being
interested in various different sports
I'm obsessed with one thing for a year
and then another thing for a year and
then I kind of jump around like that and
recently with age two things have been
on my mind one is like training one
thing I've never done to get better
physically at any of the sports I've
done is train I mean the boring stuff
like weights drills yoga all that stuff
to get better at biking or climbing I've
only ever done more biking or more
climbing the other thing I've been
thinking about is what do I consume
because I think that what I eat and
drink is not good through running this
YouTube channel I've met and spoken to a
bunch of really high level athletes and
I've noticed a stark difference between
what I eat and drink and what they eat
and drink notably there's a lot more
alcohol in my diet than theirs like I
love a beer after a hard day days work
or a glass of wine with a great bowl of
pasta It's just but when I look into how
to stay trim and fit and prolong my
health um I look at what is the easiest
thing to cut out first and alcohol seems
to be the low hanging fruit and as I
meet more high performance individuals
Not Just Sports people I start to wonder
does anyone who performs at a really
high level drink at all anyway when
these two things were kind of on my mind
I just so happened to get a call from
YouTube and Eurosport offering me a
chance to go to the Paris 2024 Olympics
they wanted me to go to the city soak it
in soak in the atmosphere and see some
of the games so I leapt at the chance to
do that thanks to euros Sports coverage
with this part of the trip was an
opportunity to interview Olympic
medalists so before I knew I was in
Paris in the Press area at Champions
Park standing in line about to Rie
Olympic medalists and I was told I have
30 seconds and two questions so
naturally I asked them what was on my
mind at the time the first thing I asked
all of the athletes was how often do you
guys train thank you for speaking to me
I just want to ask you how often do you
train uh every day I train every day
yeah how many hours uh yeah per week
it's it depends but between 25 and 30
years a week okay uh yeah sometime twice
a day but uh yeah depends also when you
have a day off no uh my day off is like
an hour and a half two hours on the bike
so yeah it's not really a day
off I trained two I have two training
per days all days and I have just seven
days a week I have just only one day to
rest but all time I training sometimes
free it depends and if if you don't have
um if I have competition at the weekend
I don't have a big time to rest but it's
normal I want to Med at the Olympic gam
so it's necessary
I train Two Times by day sometime three
times I'm around uh 6 hours by day
sometime more um I try to train every de
IPL you know I run I do Judo I try to
swim I play rugby I play football and I
think this helped me so much because I
work the cardio I work everything so yes
I try to be polyvalent seven days a week
uh Monday till Friday but I train also
Sunday on the morning I play football do
I what how often do you train do I train
oh my God I train every day sometimes
twice a day um we we train from anywhere
from an hour and a half to 5 hours on
the bike and then I often do gym
sessions as well of course I expected
Olympic athletes to train a lot
obviously but the answer of like 25 to
30 hours a week really took me by
surprise how is it even possible to
recover from that much training
additionally it seems like most athletes
train at least twice a day sometimes
three times a day likely splitting
things like weight training
from cardiio into two different discret
sessions and it looks like for a lot of
them their day off still involves 2
hours of like light cardio work as a
recovery day what I really took away
from this is apart from the copious
amounts of training that they do is that
they must have recovery down to do that
much training and to recover effectively
for the next day you must have your
recovery process really really sorted
the second question I asked the athletes
was really simple and was pertinent to
what I had been thinking for the past
couple of weeks do you drink
alcohol any alcohol no no alcohol only
water sometimes
uh sometimes something with sugar but
Coca-Cola Coca-Cola not no Coca-Cola
syrup I love it with water it's so nice
and lemonade lemonade alcohol is bad for
sports uh it's like to eat a lot of
sugar it's but for sports so you need to
have to equilibrate everything because
everything it's a important in sports
when you arrive at I level like that you
need to be perfect all the time o really
when sometime we got some medals but
generally not so I'm not
so I think if I'm with my family and I
have to enjoy my M that maybe
yes um honestly no not really like I
might have a SI of champagne to
celebrate but you know not a big
drinker for sure I I invest a lot in
high performance and um I think that's
important but also I I like feeling good
and feeling healthy and that's part of
it no no no you know it's uh I need to
take care of my weight and uh so it's
alcohol is not really like fitting with
my lifestyle great thank you very much I
was pretty sure the answer going in to
this I mean they're athletes after all
but it's still kind of surprised me I
think the reason I'm surprised it's a
cultural reason like it's ingrained in
me that if you win a medal you have a
beer to celebrate I'm not sure that's a
good thing but for these guys a
celebration is you know a cheat day with
the food and then probably back to the
gym the next day I think for me this is
the kick up the backside I needed I was
so incred ibly inspired just being
around these athletes watching them walk
through the crowds of people with their
medals and then having the chance to
interview them and when I asked them a
question that I knew the answer to which
is do you drink alcohol and they said no
it was the child in me is is simply
saying well if you don't someone who I
look up to and admire then I won't
either and that's what I think I'm going
to do I think I'm done with it at least
for the foreseeable future
I'm going to stop drinking alcohol to be
clear I already drink very little
alcohol um I just think that my
association with success and celebration
and relaxation is is alcohol the the
connection is is is in my brain and
these Olympians don't have that I'm
going to see how how I feel just cutting
it out of my system completely am I
going to feel better am I not going to
notice any difference am I going to lose
some weight as for the copious amounts
of training I think just
doing as an Olympian does and jumping in
with 30 hours of training a week to get
better at your sport is a pretty dumb
idea I think that's a quick way to get
burned out these guys are Elites and I
can't copy that part of their program I
think that what I've taken away is that
probably some deliberate training that
is not actually just doing the sport as
in not just climbing or biking but
actually doing some weights for climbing
or or some physiotherapy to get rid of
that shoulder injury I think that kind
of training would be really beneficial
for me and I think I would really enjoy
doing that I've never done any
deliberate training outside of the sport
that I do anyway this is just a short
one to let you know sort of what I took
away from my opportunity to interview
these athletes was only two questions
but I took a lot from it um enjoy the
games they're still ongoing at the time
of publishing this video so go and check
them out thank you very much to YouTube
and EUR support for flying me out to
Paris and giving me the VIP treatment
you can stream every moment of the Paris
2024 Olympic Games on Discovery plus
thanks very much to you for watching I
hope you enjoyed it we've got a couple
of videos in the works so check back
later for more thank you very much catch
you next time peace